是，大臣  第2季第1集
THE LAST FANTASY | TLF HALFCD TeaM
压制：beiming6@TLF  字幕：破烂熊
仅供交流  严禁商用
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译: tpring  校对: i1984
仁爱社会
今天忙什么呢 先生?      内阁开会
What is it today, sir?           The Ministry.
一上午讨论公共医疗卫生的事
All morning on Health service administration.
啊 收音机里刚刚还在播
A chap just now on the radio
说公共医疗 教育和卫生的问题
said the trouble with health,education and transport
在于政府官员都去私立医院
is that people in Governmentgo to private hospitals
把孩子送去私立学校      好好
and send their kidsto private schools.        Very good.
喜剧节目吧?
Comedy programme, was it?
上班都坐公家车
And go to workin chauffeur-driven cars.
多少有点道理吧 先生?
Think there's something in it, sir?
如果您和汉弗莱爵士搭公交上班
If you and Sir Humphreywent to work on a number 27...
不切实际
Quite impracticable!
我们工作时间够长了
We work long enough hours as it is,
哪有空等公交
without having to wait at bus stops.
你们需要更有效率的公交      可不是
You'd need more efficient buses.Certainly would.
对 广播也是这么说的
Yes, that's what he was saying.
医疗系统也一样 您加入联合福利协会了吧 先生?
Same with the Health Service.You a member of BUPA, sir?
现在在播什么 罗伊?      "昨日议会" 先生
Anything on the radio, Roy?"Yesterday in Parliament".
还是算了...
Don't bother...
兰弗先生 伯明翰的反对党成员
Mr Lanford,opposition member for Birmingham,
询问行政事务大臣吉姆·哈克
asked the AdministrativeAffairs Minister, James Hacker,
公共医疗行政减员一事
about reducing administratorsin the Health Service.
是的 我们已经削减了11.3%
We have already achieveda reduction of 11.3 %
书记和管理人员
in administrative staff
经济效益正在稳步提高
and are actively pursuingfurther economies.
大臣能否解释一下您对下院的保证
Would you explainhow his assurance to the House
为何与您部里的会议记录不同?
squares with this minutefrom his own department?
于是 兰弗先生戏剧化地拿出一张纸
Then Mr Lanford dramaticallyproduced a paper.
原文:"如果将行政人员重新分类"
I quote,"If admin staff were reclassified
"改为技术头衔"
from administrativeto technical...
"单位由财政年转为公历年"
and the comparison changedfrom the financial to calendar year,
"统计数字就会减少11.3%"
then the figures will showa fall of 11.3 %".
大臣能否解释一下这阴谋诡计?
Would the Minister care to commenton this shabby deception?
上套了 先生
Bit of a googly, sir.
我...我...
I... I...
我对你手里那张纸一无所知
I have no knowledge of the documentyou're brandishing.
我愿意向大臣提供文件
I shall givethe file reference to the Minister
来交换一次完全独立的调查
in exchange for an assuranceof a full independent enquiry.
我保证发起调查
I will give that assurance.
下院宣读了苏格兰渔业法案
The Houseread the Scottish Fisheries'Bill...
不好办啊 "独立调查"
That's a bit rough, innit?"A full independent enquiry"!
您被套进去了      我觉得我逃脱了
You were dropped in it there.I think I got away with it.
幸好他们没问圣爱医院的事 先生      为什么?
Lucky they didn't ask youabout that new hospital, sir.Why?
完工了15个月 还没有病人
They finished it 15 months ago,and it's still got no patients.
一定是卫生部没钱请员工
The DHSS can't afford to staff it.
有员工 500名行政人员
It's got staff, 500 administrators.
只缺病人      谁告诉你的?
Just no patients.Who told you?
我朋友查理 卫生部长的司机
My mate Charlie,a driver for the Health Secretary.
汉弗莱 我太震惊了      我也是 大臣
I'm appalled!           So am I.
玩忽职守 太不像话
The incompetence of it!
就是 真不知您中了什么邪
I can't think what came over you.
你说什么
I beg your pardon!
完全独立的调查?      汉弗莱 我不是说这个
A full independent enquiry.Humphrey, that's not what I meant.
您说玩忽职守      我是说你 汉弗莱
But you mentioned incompetence.Yours, Humphrey, yours!
我 大臣?     你害我套进去的
Mine?           You dropped me into it?
我们不能总面面俱到
We can't foresee a small omissionfrom the brief,
可是独立调查?
but a full enquiry?
我也不想被调查 但如果你落水了 有绳子就抓
I don'twant an enquiry, but ifyou're drowning and thrown a rope...
这不是绳子 这是绞索
That wasn't a rope, it was a noose!
职责要求您站在部里的立场上
You should've stood upfor the department!
不 汉弗莱 我为昨天的质询做了万全准备
I prepared thoroughlyfor yesterday's Question Time,
偏不知道你在玩弄数据
but nowhere was the suggestionyou'd juggled the figures
让我误导下院
so I'd mislead the House.
大臣 您吩咐减少行政人员数目 我们就减少数目
You wanted the figures reduced?So we reduced the figures!
对 但没减少行政人员      当然没有
Yes, but not the administrators.Of course not.
这不是我的本意      大臣 我们可没有心灵感应
That's not what I meant.Minister, one isn't a mind-reader!
您说减数目 我们就减数目      还有一件事
You said reduce them, so we did.And another thing:
他们怎么知道的?又一次泄漏?
How did this get out?Another leak?
这哪是行政部 简直是漏锅
This isn't a department,it's a colander!
什么都告诉后座议员
How can we govern responsibly,
怎能权责分明?
if back benchers get all the facts?
调查给了我们缓冲时间      那就是定时炸弹
The enquiry gives us some time.So does a time-bomb.
有没有抢险队?      抢险队?
Is there a disposal squad?Disposal squad?
能否让独立调查为我们开脱?
Couldn't we get the independentenquiry to exonerate us?
您想操纵调查?      没有没有
Do you mean rig it?No, no, no, no!
这个...对
Well... yes.
大臣
Minister!
这取决于主席是谁
It depends on who the chairman is.
他一定得可靠      怎么个可靠法?
He absolutely has to be sound.Sound?
得有觉悟 一点就通
He will knowwhat is required.He will perceive the implications.
有洞察力 对我们抱同情
He will have a sympathetic insightinto the problems.
总而言之 他得可靠
In short, he will be "sound".
你是说...收买他?
You mean... bent?
不 当然不是
No, of course not!
他得自己心胸宽大
He will be a manof broad understanding.
那就...找退休政客?
How about... a retired politician?
正直得无懈可击
And unimpeachable integrity.
对 我懂你的意思
Yes, I see what you mean.
商人?      哦 开玩笑
A businessman?Oh, really!
学者?      不 不 不
An academic?No, no, no.
你想找谁?      我想 退休公务员也许可以
Who've you got in mind?Perhaps a retired civil servant.
好主意 汉弗莱      莫里斯·威廉爵士
Good thinking, Humphrey.Sir Maurice Williams.
他不会太独立吧?
Might not he be too independent?
他想要个贵族头衔      就靠这个?
Well, he's hoping for a peerage.Not through this?
不 可是出对了结论能攒工分
No, but the right findingwill earn him Brownie points!
工分?      攒够了换徽章嘛
Brownie points?They all add up towards the badge!
好吧 就找莫里斯爵士      谢谢您 大臣
Well, Sir Maurice it is.Thank you, Minister.
谢谢 大队长
Thank you... Brown Owl.
早安 伯纳
Good morning, Bernard.
两件事 首先是古巴难民      又来了
Two points, the Cuban refugees.Not that again?
关于我们拒绝出台更多优惠政策
It's about our refusalto do any more for them.
不怪我 怪财政部 谁能对抗财政部      没错
It's not my fault, it's the Treasury.You can't beat the Treasury!
我不表态
I shall say nothing.
再公开丢一次脸
One more public humiliation
我自己都成政治难民了
and I'llbecome a political refugee myself.
还有一件呢?      您问伦敦北郊那间空壳医院
And the other point?The alleged empty hospital.
对对      我提醒过您 司机消息网并不完全可靠
As I warned you, the driver's networkis not wholly reliable.
罗伊说错了      谢天谢地
Roy's wrong.Thank heavens forthat!
怎么查到的?      私人秘书消息网
How did you find out?The private secretaries' network.
详情呢?
And?
实际上医院里行政人员只有342名
In fact, there are only 342administrative staff at the hospital.
其他170人是门房 清洁工 洗衣工和厨子之类
The other 170 are porters, cleaners,laundry workers, cooks, etc.
医护人员呢?
And medical staff?
那倒没有
Oh, none of them.
没有?      没有
None?             No!
伯纳 我们说的是圣爱医院吧?
We are talkingabout St Edward's Hospital?
是 刚落成15个月 人员齐备
Yes. It's brand-new and fully-staffed.
不幸赶上政府削减预算
Unfortunately, there were cutbacks,
所以没钱开展医疗了
so there was no moneyfor medical services.
一家新医院 500名行政人员 没医生 没病人?
A hospital with over 500 non-medicalstaff and no patients?
有一名病人      一名?
There's one patient.One?
副主管绊在脚手架上 摔断了腿
The deputy administrator fell overscaffolding and broke his leg.
老天爷
Good God!
幸好下院没问 为什么消息没泄漏?
Thank heavens I wasn't askedabout this! Why hasn't it got out?
实际上 它被打扮成工地
It's been contrivedto look like a building site,
至今没人发现它开业了
and so far no one's realisedit's operational!
像脚手架 水泥车 正常工程用品
You know, scaffolding, skips,the normal thing?
正常?我得赶在反对党前面去看看
Normal? I'd better look at itbefore the opposition does.
对 很奇怪媒体还没发现
Yes, it's surprisingthe press haven't found out.
伯纳 幸好大多数记者素质底下
Fortunately, most journalistsare so incompetent,
大概连今天星期三都不知道
they wouldn't knowtoday is Wednesday.
今天是星期四 大臣
It's actually Thursday, Minister.
就坐那边
Let's sit down there.
你们大臣干吗对圣爱医院感兴趣?
Why is your Minister interestedin this hospital?
他很担心那里没病人
He's greatly concernedthat it has no patients.
林子大了      就是
It takes all sorts.           Yes.
晚上好      晚上好
Evening.Good evening.
没有医护人员哪来的病人?      就是
How can there be patientswhen it has no nursing staff?
谢谢      太好了
Thank you.Splendid.
汉弗莱爵士      谢谢
Sir Humphrey?Thank you.
卫生部认为开业需要时间
We've found at the DHSSthat it takes time to get things going.
首先得安排好
First of all, you have to sort out
日常运转
the smooth running of the hospital.
收治病人可不能改善现状
Having patients aroundwould be no help at all.
他们只会碍事
They'd just be in the way.
告诉他现在是磨合期      对 磨合期
Tell him this is the run-in period.Yes, yes, the run-in period.
要磨合多久?你看
How long is the run-in periodgoing to last?
我们大臣承诺发起独立调查
My Minister's agreedto an independent enquiry.
你知道我最恨这个      我知道 可是...
You knowwhat I think about that.Yes, I know, but...
我们会给圣爱医院找些病人
We are going to getsome patients in to St Edward's...
终究会吧?
eventually?
不是吗?
Aren't we?
有可能
It's possible.
确实有这个意向
Certainly our present intention.
一两年之内
In a year or two.
大概...等财政状况改善点
Probably... when the financialsituation has eased up a bit.
此前不会吗?      不
Not till then?            No
到处都在关闭 怎能破例开40个新病房?
How can I open 40 new wardswhen I'm closing everywhere else?
财政部和内阁都会反对      我们大臣可能要关闭它
Treasury wouldn't wear it.My Minister may want to shut the place.
不可能 工会怎么办?
Impossible! What about the unions?
已经有工会了?      这倒是
Are the unions active there yet?Good point.
记得在萨瑟医院煽风点火那人吗?
Remember that fire brand agitatorat Southwark Hospital?
比利·弗雷泽 讨厌鬼 可能有用
Billy Fraser, odious man.Could be useful.
该放他出马了
Time he was moved on.
卫生部门正在官僚之路上高歌猛进
The Health Service is an advancedcase of galloping bureaucracy!
怎能说高歌猛进
Oh, certainly not galloping!
最多算稳步前进
A gentle canterat the most.
每天有报告涌进来 对吧伯纳      哪来的 大臣?
Instances flood into this office.From whom, Minister?
议员 选民 医生 护士 公众
MPs, constituents,doctors, nurses, the public.
刁民
Trouble makers!
公众?      他们最不安分
The public?They're the worst.
听听这个
Listen to this.
"申请听诊器:基于目前状况"
"Stethoscope requisition:Due to current situation,
"无法按需核发听诊器"
it is not possible to issuethe extra stethoscopes applied for.
"但可以为现有听诊器"
We can, however,supply longertubes
"配备更长的胶管"
for your existing stethoscopes".
怎么了?      你不觉得奇怪吗?
Well?Doesn't that strike you as odd?
不 如果增加胶管...      不 不
Lf they have long tubes...No, no.
他们不要长胶管 要听诊器
No, not longer stethoscopes,MORE stethoscopes.
如果胶管够长
If they had really long tubes,
医生可以坐在原地 听遍所有病人
the doctor could stand in one placeand listen to all the chests.
这个呢? "护士制服"
What about nurses' uniforms?
"显然目前标准制服"
"Apparently the latestconsignment of nurses' coats
"均以半透明材料制作"
is made of a see-through material;nurses issued with these
"护士请求上报制服监督委员会"
are requested to reportto the Directorof Uniform Surveillance,
"评估问题严重程度"
who will assessthe extent of the problem".
这倒是个美差      汉弗莱 我说真的!
Nice work if you can get it.Humphrey, I'm serious!
"请注意 柔软型卫生纸专供病人而非职工"
"Please note that the soft toiletrolls are for patients not staff.
"似乎近来职工在用柔软型卫生纸"
It would appear that staff havebeen using the soft toilet rolls
"作此种或彼种用途"
for one reason or another".
"圣史蒂芬太平间圣诞期间将关闭"
"St Stephen's Mortuarywill be closed over Christmas.
"节日期间 请医护人员"
During the holiday,medical staff are to cooperate
"减轻太平间负担"
in keeping pressureoff this department".
非常合理 情有可原
A very civil and reasonable request.
平常医生该让太平间繁荣昌盛吗?
You think the rest of the yeardoctors work hard to keep it busy?
大臣 这些都是特例
These are a few isolated examples.
大体上 医疗部门已达到政府最高效率
The Health Service is as efficientas the Government allows it.
胡说 汉弗莱 看数字就知道
Nonsense!The figures speak for themselves.
10年来 医疗部门行政人员增加了4万名
In ten years, the number ofadministrators has risen by 40,000.
病床减少了6万张
The number of hospital bedshas fallen by 60,000.
医疗年度支出增加了1500万 净增长
The annual cost of the HealthService has gone up by ?.5 billion!
工业增长也有这个速度就好了
If only British industrycould match this growth record.
你觉得多拨款少治病人
You think spendingmore money on fewer patients
余钱拿来雇行政人员
so we can employmore administrators
是对国会和纳税人负责吗?
is a good way of spendingthe taxpayer's money?
当然
Certainly.
汉弗莱 拨款是为了把病人治好 要专款专用
This money is solelyto make sick people better.
不不 大臣
No, no, no, Minister.
是为了我们大家好
It is to make everybody better.
更好体现大家的关注与仁爱之心
Better for showing the extentof their care and compassion.
您看 当款项集中投入医疗或社会服务
You see, when money is allocatedto the Health orSocial Services,
议会和国民都觉得...升华了
Parliament and the countryfeel...cleansed.
净化了 赎罪了 这是种牺牲
Purified. Absolved. It is a sacrifice.
花言巧语
Dreadful claptrap!
牺牲仪式之后
After the sacrifice is made,
没人会问祭品去了哪里
nobody questionswhat happened to the offering.
汉弗莱 你错了 公众确实反对滥用
The public does careif it's misspent.
恕我直言 他们反对公开滥用
They care it's not seento be misspent.
才不是呢 看看那桩精神病院丑闻
That's not true. Look at the uproarover mental hospital scandals.
正是如此 大臣
My point exactly.
顺顺当当浪费了多少年 几十年
Those abuses had been going onhappily for years.
没人关心钱花到哪去了
Nobody was concernedwhat was being done with their money.
他们只恨知道了真相
What outraged themwas being told.
汉弗莱 多世故的烟幕弹
A cynical smokescreen!
你我都同意
Are we or are we not agreed
医院不能专养行政人员吧?
there's no pointin a hospital run solelyforthe staff?
我不会这么说      我会
That's not how I would express it.It's how I would.
确实
Indeed.
那你怎么说?      当然 总的来说
How would you express it?At the end of the day,
治病救人是医院的职能之一
one of a hospital's prime functionsis patient care.
之一?还有什么?
One?
没有钱请医护人员
Until we have the moneyfor nursing and medical staff,
这一职能18个月内不能履行
it's a function we can't pursue.In 18 months orso...
18个月?      届时可以开些病房
18 months?We can open some wards.
不行 汉弗莱 必须现在病房全开
No, it's got to be now.
好吧 那就组成部门联席委员会
I suppose we could forman inter-departmental committee
考察提早收治病人
to examine the feasibilityof monitoring a proposal
这一提案的可行性
for admitting patients earlier.
出结果要多久?      不久
How long would that take to report?Not long.
多久?      大概18个月
How long?About 18 months.
我提议裁掉所有人员
I suggestwe get ridof all the staff there
省下钱开放其他医院闲置病房      大臣
and use the money to openclosed wards in other hospitals.
等有钱了 再给圣爱医院配备医生开业 您可同意?
When we can afford it, we openSt Edward's with medical staff.
大臣 如此您把开业时间推后了好几年
Do that and you'll delaythe opening for patients for years.
为什么      您觉得没病人 行政人员就闲着?
Why?You talk as if the staffhave nothing to do!
有什么事      拜托 大臣
What do they do?Really, Minister!
各部门都非常繁忙
There's a large numberof extremely busy departments.
首先 有应急科预防火灾 罢工 空袭
Firstly, the Contingency Departmentforfires, strikes, air raids,
核战争 瘟疫 食物或饮水污染
nuclearwar, epidemics,food or water poisoning.
一旦险情发生 医院是救治中心
In such a crisis, the hospitalis a key centre for survival.
其次 数据研究科
Then, the Data and ResearchDepartment,
总结分析
conducting a full-scale
辖区内各项数据
demographicsurvey of the catchment area.
必须预计未来孕妇生产率
We have to anticipate the futurerequirements for maternity,
老龄率 幼儿率和男女比率
geriatrics, paediatricsand the male/female balance.
第三当然是财务科
Thirdly, there'sFinance projected accounts,
平衡账面与现金周转
balance sheetsand cash-flow budgets.
还有采购科
Then, the Purchasing Department
采购医疗物资
for purchasing medical equipment,
核查估价 管理分类报价单
examining estimates, lookingat price lists and catalogues...
采购什么?
Purchasing what?
什么都有 大臣
Everything, Minister.
从脑波扫描仪到清洁剂 我接着说?
Everything from brain scannersto Brasso! May I continue?
简短些说
Be briefer.
我尽量 大臣 不过您得理解
Would that I could, Minister,but you need to understand.
第五 技术科 评估设备的
Fifth, the Technical Departmentfor evaluations.
第六 土建科 主管第三期工程
Sixth, the Building Departmentdealing with Phase 3 plans,
成本及施工 确保1994年完工
costing and so forth for the finalphase to be completed by 1994.
然后还有维修 清洁 炊事科
Then, there's Maintenance,Cleaning and Catering,
有人管理休假 健康保险 工资
Personnel in charge of leave,National Health Insurance, salaries,
以及福利人员照顾这500名员工
as well as staff welfare officersto look after the 500 employees.
最后 主管部门      主管部门
And finally, Administration.Administrators!
增加行政人员来管行政人员
More administrators administratingother administrators!
这工作至关重要 大臣
This is important work, Minister.
打字小组 文具 办工家具及设备
The typing pool, stationery,office furniture and equipment.
部门关系协调      你是说真的?
Liaison between departments.Are you being serious ornot?
怎么讲      汉弗莱 没有病人啊
What do you mean?There are NO patients!
医院干什么的?看病!
That is what a hospital's for.Patients!
悬壶济世 治病救人
Ill people! Healing the sick!
可是大臣 这些基本工作和病人不相干
But all these vital tasks mustbe done with or without patients.
为什么?
Why?
为什么?      为什么?
Why?          Why?
我不明白
I don't understand.
还得怎么说?为什么?
How else can I express it? Why?
不打仗您就遣散军队吗?
Would you sack the armybecause there's no war?
两码事 医院必须出效益
Completely different!A hospital must produce results.
大臣 效益不看结果 得看行动 现在医院很景气
We don't measure our successby results but by activity.
这500人已经操劳过度了
Those 500 peopleare seriously overworked.
预计编制有650人
The full establishmentshould be 650.
您要看医院的报告吗?
May I show you the paperwork?
不 汉弗莱 我看够了 全部裁掉
No, Humphrey.Enough is enough. Sack them!
办不到 大臣
Out of the question, Minister.
没有行政人员 医院永不能开业
We need administratorsor the hospital will never open.
裁掉后勤工人      也不行 工会不同意
Sack the ancillary staff.The unions won'twear it.
各裁一半 省下钱来请医生护士
Sack half and use the moneyto get doctors and nurses,
开几个病房
and open some wards!
不 汉弗莱 这是我的底线 底线!
No, Humphrey, that's my lastword.My lastword!
你可以走了
You may go!
很好 大臣 我去和医疗工会协商
Very well, Minister.I shall have a word with the unions.
但我不抱希望      快走
But I don't hold out much hope.Go!
就这些 感谢各位到会
That seems to be everything.Thank you forcoming.
谢谢大家
Thank you very much.
讨论的不错      谢谢
Very good meeting.Yes very good.
布赖恩 留下喝一杯?      得尽快
Got time fora drink?           A quick one.
照旧?别客气
The usual? Make yourself at home.
谢谢
Thank you.
圣爱医院怎么办?
What are we going to doabout St Edward's?
圣爱医院?
St Edward's Hospital?
我们不占理 就照你的来
Not much of a case.Can't fight you on it.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
我们承认不能在空壳医院里养后勤人员
We realise you can't keep ancillarystaff on in an empty hospital.
会不会太悲观了?
Isn't that a bit defeatist?
什么?
What?
你们不会不管他们吧?      你是说...
Surely, you can stick up forthem?You want us to...?
可不是你们一方的事
It's not just your workers, you know?
那342名公务员得有人可管理
The 342 civil servants must havesome workers to administer.
怎会裁到公务员头上?      时世艰难啊
Civil servants are never laid off.We live in disturbing times.
你是说 我们全行业反抗 你会支持?
You mean, if we take industrialaction, you'll support us?
亲爱的布赖恩 我是常任秘书
My dear Brian,I am the Permanent Secretary.
我的职责是维持政府运转
My task is to turnthe wheels of government.
我怎么能支持罢工呢
I couldn't possibly countenanceany such action.
不过...如果各位工友
But... if there wereeffective opposition
强烈施压
from the ancillary workers,
公务员也会支持
the civil servantswould have to stay.
大臣呢?
And the Minister?
大臣自己连蓝领白领都分不清
The Ministerdoesn't knowhis ACAS from his NALGO.
我没什么优势 你看
I haven't got much of a case.
医院空了15个月 病房一年内开不了
Hospital empty for 15 months,wards not open for another year.
振作点
Pull yourself together.
想想会员们的妻儿老小
Think of yourmembers' wives and children.
家里的猫咪...鹦鹉
Their... cats... budgies!
会员都认命了
They're resigned to it by now.
比利·弗雷泽也认命啦?
Is Billy Fraser resigned to it?
这倒是...可他还在萨瑟医院
Yes... but he's overat Southwark.
你敢肯定?
Do you want to bet?
你是说...?
You mean...?
那就不一样了 工人们就缺人撑腰壮胆
Well, that's a different matter,with some real shop-floor militancy.
明白了?团结一心 众志成城
You see? Unity. Solidarity.
谢谢你的酒      谢谢你 阶级兄弟
Thanks for the drink.Thank you, Brother.
请替我问候各位战友
Please give my kind regardsto our fraternal comrades.
"任你东南西北风 我们就不动"
We shall not,we shall not be moved!
大臣 这位是行政总管罗杰夫人
Minister, this is Mrs Rogers,the chief administrator.
您好您好      比利·弗雷泽 工会主席
Nice to meet you.Billy Fraser, committee chairman.
幸会幸会      我看不见得
Hownice to meet you.I wouldn't be too sure.
这是F病区
This is 'F' ward.
这是J手术室
And this is 'J' theatre.
总造价多少?      加上放射治疗仪和监护仪
Howmuch did all this cost?With radio therapy...
225万磅
two and a quartermillion.
完全闲置 真可怕      不 也可以说是幸运
It's appalling it's not used!No, a very good thing in some ways.
延长使用寿命 降低运作成本
Prolongs its life,cuts down running costs.
可是没有病人啊
But there are no patients!
没有 本职工作仍然得完成
But essential work has to go on.
治病不是本职工作?
Aren't patients essential work?
管理500人是个大工程 大臣
Running an organisationof 500 people is a big job.
但没有人就没有工作了嘛      什么?
But if they weren't here,they wouldn't be here!
这不对头 不能这样下去
This is wrong. It won't do.
再不收病人 我就关闭医院
Either get some patientsor I'll close it.
总有一天 大臣...      别"总有一天" 马上!
Well, in the course of time...Not in the course of time. Now!
裁掉300名员工 雇些医生 收些病人
Get rid of 300 staff, get somedoctors and get some patients!
且慢 少了300人 医院没法运转
Without those 300 peoplethis hospital wouldn't function!
现在在运转吗?
And it's functioning now?
大臣 这是国内运转最良好的医院之一
Minister, it's one of the best-runhospitals in the country.
准备拿南丁格尔奖的
It's up fora Florence Nightingale Award.
什么奖项?      "本区最卫生的医院"
What, pray, is that?"The Most Hygienic Hospital".
罗杰夫人 我话说到头了 必须裁300人
I've said my last word.300 staff must go.
300人失业?      只剩骨干人员 怎么动大手术?
300 jobs lost?            Surgery with a skeleton staff?
别动大手术 治治静脉曲张 痔疮 什么都好
Don't do any surgery. Do varicoseveins, piles... Do something!
你要让300人失业?      没错 弗雷泽先生
You mean 300 jobs lost?          Yes, I do.
医院不是就业处 它是治病用的
A hospital is a placefor healing of the sick!
它是我们会员的衣食父母 你要裁掉他们
It's employment for my members,and you want to sack them.
这算哪门子"仁爱社会"?
Is that your compassionate society?
对病人仁爱 不是对你们会员
Compassionate to patientsrather than your members!
好 我们会罢工抗议
We'll come out on strike.
太好了 快去
Very well, do that.
有什么关系?罢工更好 快去快去
Who can it harm? Do, please!Strike, the sooner the better!
带上行政人员一起 省得我们发工资了
Take the administrators with you.Then we shan't have to pay you.
下班前喝一杯如何 伯纳?      好的 谢谢 大臣
How about a drink before home?Yes. Thank you, Minister.
咱们在医院大获全胜吧?      是 大臣
That went well at the hospital.Yes, Minister.
我立场坚定 毫不退让      对 大臣
I wasn't standing any argument.No, Minister.
罢工!正中我下怀 干杯      干杯
Threatening to strike!Played right into my hands. Cheers!
新闻快开始了吧?
Aren't we missing the news?
分社发回消息 美国正在施压
Our diplomatic correspondentsays the US is pressuring the UK
要求英国接收古巴难民
to take Cuban refugees.
政府不予置评
The Governmenthas made no comment.
当然 没钱嘛
Got no money.
伦敦所有公立医院的工人
All workers in London hospitals
从周五午夜起展开罢工
are to go on strikeat Friday midnight.
好...什么?
Right... What?
导火索来自伦敦圣爱医院
A row has blown upat St Edward's
决定辞退170名工友
over the proposed laying-offof 170 ancillary workers.
我们采访了工会活动家比利·弗雷泽
We spoke to activist Billy Fraser.
我们以罢工抗议失业
We're strikingagainst unemployment.
我们能让全伦敦的医院瘫痪
We can bring London's hospitalsto a complete standstill.
没法输血 没法手术
There'll beno blood transfusions,
没法治疗癌症 全部停摆
no cancertreatment, nothing!
直到他们贯彻"仁爱社会"
Till we havethe compassionate society.
你们怎能这样对待病人?      不是我们 是哈克的错
How can you do this to patients?It's Mr Hackerthat's doing it.
一定要殃及无辜民众吗?
But you're inflicting terriblesanctions on the innocent public.
借此机会 我向媒体和公众保证
I'd like to take this opportunityto assure the general public,
不解决问题我们绝不动摇
every stone will be left unturnedin a search for a settlement.
看新闻了吗?你说你跟工会协商的      对 我知道
Have you seen the news?You said you'd talk to the unions!
这下怎么办?      还有更严重的问题
What are we going to do?We have a more serious problem.
莫里斯爵士领导的独立调查
Sir Maurice's independent enquiryabout the department.
对我们不利
It's unfavourable to us.
你说他可靠的 他不是想做贵族吗
You said he was sound!
没错 但贵族头衔也关系到
I know, but he's also workingas chairman
他是难民安置委员会主席
of the Refugee ResettlementCommittee.
明白了 难民比调查更能加分
There are more Brownie pointsfor refugees than enquiries!
正是 大臣
Precisely, Minister.
他不知道我们没钱安置难民?
We've no moneyto re-house the refugees.
大臣?      挂掉 我不想接
Minister?I don'twant to talk!
是首相府
It's Number 10...
您好 我是...
Hello, Ji...
对 没错
Yes. Quite.
明白了
I see.
没关系 谢谢您
Not at all. Thank you.
首相府看到了弗雷泽的新闻
They've seen Fraser on the news.
要求马上讲和
They want a peace formula soon.
莫里斯爵士说他只要求
Sir Maurice says he'll be satisfied
英国安置1000名难民
only if the UKwill house1,000 refugees.
没钱给难民 医院的1000个床位都还...
Butwe haven't the money.Or for 1,000 hospital beds...
他有多少难民?      1000个
How many refugees?           1,000.
1000难民 1000床位 人员齐备
1,000 refugees? 1,000 beds!
大臣 医院要服务英国病人 不是外国健康人
Minister, that hospital isfor sick British not healthy foreigners!
还有很多人需要...      你不是说
There's a huge waiting list.Didn't you just say
莫里斯爵士的调查对我们不利?
Sir Maurice's enquiry was likelyto come down against us?
那是...      难道你愿意?
That's a...That what you want?
我明白了 大臣
I see your point, Minister.
伯纳 召回圣爱医院所有工人
Bernard, reinstate all the workersat St Edward's.
告诉莫里斯爵士我们有家新医院
Tell Sir Mauricewe can offer a new hospital,
可容纳1000名难民
with accommodationfor 1,000 refugees.
告诉媒体是我的决策 皆大欢喜
Tell the press itwas my decisionand that everybody's happy.
要引您的话吗 大臣?      怎么不要?就写
Do want to give a quote, Minister?Why not? Say...
"抉择很艰难 但不得不做"
"It was a tough decision,but a necessary one.
"为了维护不列颠..."
If Britain is to retainthe name of...
"仁爱社会" 大臣?      谢谢
"The compassionate society"?Thank you.
"仁爱社会之美名" 记下了 伯纳?
"The compassionate society".Got that?
是 大臣
Yes, Minister.